<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Devices examples on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/device-examples/</link><description>Recent content in Devices examples on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/documentation/device-examples/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Button</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/device-examples/simplebutton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/device-examples/simplebutton/</guid><description>Description The simplebutton is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. You can take any Button you want to. Like for example this one: Arcade Button Tth Template Class gives you the option to check the state of the button, and to create simple events if the button is pressed or depressed. The class implements the simpleInput template.
Layout Code A simple example on how to use the Button-Class from the Hardware-Catalog :</description></item><item><title>Simple LED</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/device-examples/simpleled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/device-examples/simpleled/</guid><description>Description The simpleLED (src/main/java/com/pi4j/example/components) is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. You can take any LED you want to. Like for example this one: LED
The template Class gives you the option to switch off, switch on or toggle the state of the LED.
Layout Code A simple example on how to use the LED-Class from the Hardware-Catalog :
// Create a new SimpleLED component SimpleLED led = new SimpleLED(pi4j, 26); // Turn on the LED to have a defined state led.</description></item><item><title>Joystick</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/device-examples/joystick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/device-examples/joystick/</guid><description>Description The Joystick (src/main/java/com/pi4j/example/components) is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. The template is created for a digital joystick with 4 directions (up, right, down, left) and as an option additionally with a push button in direction down. A suitable hardware component is: : Joystick
The template class allows to query the individual joystick positions and can trigger a simple event when the joystick swings out in a direction or when it returns to the center position.</description></item></channel></rss>