<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CrowPi on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/crowpi/</link><description>Recent content in CrowPi on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/crowpi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Electronics with CrowPi</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/crowpi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/crowpi/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-example-crowpi
For this example we are going to use a CrowPi, which is a starter kit in a laptop-housing. Of course, you can get any electronics starter kit for this purpose or buy separate components. That&amp;rsquo;s the fun of electronics: components are inexpensive and easy to find on ebay or one of the many web shops.
CrowPi 1
CrowPi 2
Example electronics starter kit
As the CrowPi contains a lot of components, this example is described on the following subpages:</description></item><item><title>CrowPi OS</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/crowpi/crowpi-os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/crowpi/crowpi-os/</guid><description>You can start experimenting with the default Raspberry Pi OS, but to make things easier a prepackaged OS is available with additional tools. Follow these steps to get started quickly with this CrowPi OS.
Install the Raspberry Pi Imager The official Imager Tool can be downloaded directly from the Raspberry Pi website. This simple tool works on all common operating systems and can be installed very easily with just a few keystrokes.</description></item><item><title>Develop with Intellij IDEA</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/crowpi/develop-with-intellij/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/crowpi/develop-with-intellij/</guid><description>In this tutorial, IntelliJ IDEA is used for the development. The articles, instructions and pictures are created accordingly. IntelliJ IDEA is from available Jetbrains in different versions. The community version has enough functionality for development with the CrowPi and is available for Windows, MacOS and Linux, but NOT for Raspberry Pi. The download can be found here.
The subsequent setup of IntelliJ IDEA is identical on all platforms.
Clone the repository As soon as we have installed the development environment, it is time to clone the entry-level project for the CrowPi.</description></item></channel></rss>