<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Components on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/</link><description>Recent content in Components on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/examples/components/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Simple Button</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/simplebutton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/simplebutton/</guid><description>Description The SimpleButton is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project.
The Template Class gives you the option to check the state of the button, and to create simple events if the button is pressed, depressed or while it is being pressed.
Layout Simple Button Breadboard
Big Button
Code A simple example on how to use the Button-Class from the Hardware-Catalog :</description></item><item><title>Simple LED</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/simpleled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/simpleled/</guid><description>Description The SimpleLED is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project.
The template Class gives you the option to switch off, switch on or toggle the state of the LED.
Layout Simple Led Breadboard
Code A simple example on how to use the LED-Class from the Hardware-Catalog :</description></item><item><title>AD Converter ADS1115</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ads1115/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ads1115/</guid><description>Description The Analog Digital Converter ADS1115 is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. The ADS1115 device is a precision, low-power, 16-bit, I2C-compatible, analog-to-digital converter (ADCs). The ADS1115 device incorporates a low-drift voltage reference and an oscillator as well as a programmable gain amplifier (PGA) and a digital comparator. These features, along with a wide operating supply range, makes the ADS1115 well suited for power- and space-constrained, sensor measurement applications.</description></item><item><title>Buzzer</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/buzzer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/buzzer/</guid><description>Description The Buzzer is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project.
The Template Class gives you the option to play a note, and to create your own little melodies to play. The buzzer is controlled via a PWM output. The dutycycle is fixed at 50% and with the frequency the desired sound can be reproduced.
Layout Buzzer Acitve Breadboard
Buzzer Active</description></item><item><title>Camera</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/camera/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/camera/</guid><description>Description The Camera is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. Currently, the code is only tested with a Raspberry-Camera and the crowpi-image. You can take pictures or videos, with or without a preview.
To connect the camera, use this video. The video is mentioned on the official website. The camera class is using the bash-commands &amp;ldquo;libcamera-hello&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;libcamera-still&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;libcamera-vid&amp;rdquo;. To use them, set up the raspberry with the following Introduction</description></item><item><title>Joystick</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/joystick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/joystick/</guid><description>Description The Joystick is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. The template is created for a digital joystick with 4 directions (up, right, down, left) and as an option additionally with a push button in direction down. A suitable hardware component is the arcade joystick in the picture bellow. But any joystick with switching contacts will meet the requirements.
The template class allows to query the individual joystick positions and can trigger a simple event when the joystick swings out in a direction or when it returns to the center position.</description></item><item><title>Joystick Analog</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/joystickanalog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/joystickanalog/</guid><description>Description The JoystickAnalog is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. The template class is created for an analog joystick, for example the KY-023, which consists of two potentiometers, one for the X-axis and one for the Y-axis. But any joystick with two potentiometers will meet the requirements.
The basic functions of the template class are:
return of a normalized value, optionally between 0 and 1 or between -1 and 1, of the X-axis and the Y-axis creation of simple events at a value change of the X-axis or the Y-axis, simple event handlers for button pressed, button depressed, while button is pressed calibration of the center position of the joystick (center position 0.</description></item><item><title>LCD Display</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/lcddisplay/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/lcddisplay/</guid><description>Description The LCDDisplay is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. It is used to show Numbers, Text and Symbols on a small Display. The Class supports only LCD Displays with the PCF8574T I2C Backpack. Supported display-dimensions are 40x2, 20x4, 20x2, 16x2, 16x1.
IF YOU CAN&amp;rsquo;T SEE ANYTHING WRITTEN ON THE DISPLAY, TRY TO SET THE CONTRAST BY TURNING THE CONTRAST-SCREW AT THE BACK WITH A SCREWDRIVER.</description></item><item><title>LED Button</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledbutton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledbutton/</guid><description>Description The LEDButton is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. You can take any Button with a LED you want to. Like for example the big button bellow in the picture gallery.
The Template Class gives you the option to check the state of the button, and to create simple events if the button is pressed or depressed, or the whole time is is being pressed.</description></item><item><title>LED Matrix</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledmatrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledmatrix/</guid><description>Description The LEDMatrix is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. It is an extension of the class LEDStrip. An LED matrix can be built from one LED strip. To do this, separate the LED strip at the desired point and place the individual strips under each other or next to each other. The individual ends can then be connected to each other with a wire. The constructor can be passed either as a rectangular matrix or a user-defined matrix with different numbers of LEDs in the individual strips.</description></item><item><title>LED Strip</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledstrip/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledstrip/</guid><description>Description The LEDStrip is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. You can take a LED Strip with the WS28xx-chip set.
The Template Class gives you the option to set the LED&amp;rsquo;s of the strip to a desired RGB-Color. If you have many strips, you can use the LEDMatrix
Make sure to check if SPI is enabled in your RaspberryPI. Check the SPI Address. Default is &amp;ldquo;SPI0 MOSI&amp;rdquo; Pin (#19).</description></item><item><title>Potentiometer</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/potentiometer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/potentiometer/</guid><description>Description The Potentiometer is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. The constructor of the class requires an ADS1115 object. In addition, the channel, with which the AD converter evaluates the current position of the sliding contact must be defined. For normalization, the maximum voltage that can drop across the sliding contact must also be specified. Any commercially available potentiometer with three connections (fixed resistor and the slider) can be evaluated with this class.</description></item><item><title>ServoMotor</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/servo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/servo/</guid><description>Description The ServoMotor is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. You can set the servo to a specific location, likewise to 110 degrees of it&amp;rsquo;s range.
You can use a wide variety of analog servo motors such as the SG92R or the SG-5010 (for a little more torque).
Layout Servo Breadboard
Servo SG-5010 Top View</description></item></channel></rss>