<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pi4J OS on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/pi4j-os/</link><description>Recent content in Pi4J OS on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/pi4j-os/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prepare SD with Pi4J OS</title><link>https://pi4j.com/pi4j-os/prepare-sd-with-pi4j-os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/pi4j-os/prepare-sd-with-pi4j-os/</guid><description>To prepare an SD-card with one of these flavors, download the latest build from pi4j.com/download and follow the steps described in &amp;ldquo;Set up a new Raspberry Pi, but instead of selecting one of the OS&amp;rsquo;s predefined in the Imager tool, select &amp;ldquo;Choose OS &amp;gt; Use custom&amp;rdquo;, and selected the downloaded file.
Install the Raspberry Pi Imager The official Imager Tool can be downloaded directly from the Raspberry Pi website. This simple tool works on all common operating systems and can be installed very easily with just a few keystrokes.</description></item><item><title>Develop with Intellij IDEA</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/crowpi/develop-crowpi-with-intellij/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/crowpi/develop-crowpi-with-intellij/</guid><description>The CrowPi example project contains settings to make it easy to develop on a PC with IntelliJ IDEA and execute the application on the CrowPi. The articles, instructions and pictures are created accordingly. IntelliJ IDEA is from available Jetbrains in different versions. The community version has enough functionality for development with the CrowPi and is available for Windows, MacOS and Linux, but NOT for Raspberry Pi. The download can be found here.</description></item><item><title>CrowPi examples</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/crowpi/crowpi-examples/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/crowpi/crowpi-examples/</guid><description> GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-example-crowpi
The CrowPi example code contains examples for the following components. The links in this table will bring you to the German documentation written by the students who created these examples.
Component Link 7-Segment Display seven-segment Button button Button Matrix button-matrix Buzzer buzzer Infrared Receiver ir-receiver LCD Display lcd-display LED Matrix led-matrix Light sensor light-sensor PIR Motion Sensor pir-motion-sensor Relais relay RFID rfid Step motor step-motor Servomotor servo-motor Sound Sensor sound-sensor Temperature and humidity sensor humi-temp-sens Tilt Sensor tilt-sensor Touch Sensor touch-sensor Ultrasonic distance sensor ultrasonic-sensor Vibration motor vibration-motor</description></item><item><title>Test Pi4J Basic OS</title><link>https://pi4j.com/pi4j-os/test-pi4j-basic-os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/pi4j-os/test-pi4j-basic-os/</guid><description>The Pi4J Basic OS contains two simple applications in directory java-examples and a sample file to test the audio channel. As Pi4J CrowPi OS and Pi4J Picade OS are based on Pi4J Basic OS, they also contain these tests.
You can start the tests via ssh.
Audio Test cd /home/pi nvlc Music/StarTrekTheme.mp3 Pure JavaFX Application Compile the JavaFX application
cd /home/pi/java-examples/pure-javafx javac --module-path /opt/javafx-sdk/lib --add-modules=javafx.controls,javafx.media hellofx/HelloFX.java To start HelloFX in X11-Mode</description></item><item><title>Pi4J Operating System</title><link>https://pi4j.com/pi4j-os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/pi4j-os/</guid><description>Yes, Raspberry Pi OS is great! And we made if even more awesome by adding some &amp;ldquo;goodies&amp;rdquo; for Java developers! So, to be clear, Pi4J OS is not yet another OS. It&amp;rsquo;s the official Raspberry Pi OS, with additional tools and preconfigurations to make it the ideal OS for any Java developer who wants to use a Raspberry Pi.
Additional Feature on top of Raspberry Pi OS This project provides pre-built versions of OS images with all you need to develop 100% pure Java applications for specific Raspberry Pi setups.</description></item><item><title>Test Pi4J Picade OS</title><link>https://pi4j.com/pi4j-os/test-pi4j-picade-os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/pi4j-os/test-pi4j-picade-os/</guid><description>Pi4J Picade OS contains an additional Test and the audio test should use the internal loudspeaker.
Compile the JavaFX application
cd /home/pi/java-examples/pure-picade javac --module-path /opt/javafx-sdk/lib --add-modules=javafx.controls,javafx.media hellopicade/HelloPicade.java To start HelloPicade in X11-Mode
DISPLAY=:0 XAUTHORITY=/home/pi/.Xauthority sudo -E java --module-path /opt/javafx-sdk/lib --add-modules javafx.controls,javafx.media -Dglass.platform=gtk hellopicade.HelloPicade To start HelloPicade in DRM
sudo java-kiosk hellopicade.HelloPicade Check the mapping of the Picade buttons to JavaFX KeyCodes:
Picade KeyCode Joystick up KeyCode.</description></item><item><title>Pi4J Operating System</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2023/20230731_pi4j_os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2023/20230731_pi4j_os/</guid><description>Yes, the Raspberry Pi Operating System is awesome! But the Pi4J project made it if even more awesome by adding &amp;ldquo;goodies&amp;rdquo; for Java developers! Pi4J OS is not yet another OS, but the official Raspberry Pi OS, with additional tools and preconfigurations to make it the ideal OS for any Java and JavaFX developer who wants to use a Raspberry Pi.
The project is shared on GitHub and documented on the Pi4J website.</description></item></channel></rss>