<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Development Tools on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/development/</link><description>Recent content in Development Tools on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/documentation/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Install Visual Studio Code</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/development/install-vsc-ide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/development/install-vsc-ide/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;You can develop Java applications on any computer and transfer the code or the compiled JAR-file to a Raspberry Pi to execute it. But Raspberry Pi 4 and 5 are definitely powerful enough to run an Integrated Development Environment (IDE)!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="visual-studio-code"&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visual Studio Code (VSC) is the free IDE (Integrated Developer Environment) by Microsoft. It&amp;rsquo;s designed as a universal tool that you can use for multiple programming languages with extensions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using IntelliJ IDEA</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/development/intellijidea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/development/intellijidea/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;IntelliJ IDEA is the most-used IDE for Java development. It&amp;rsquo;s also available for ARM devices but has &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea/prerequisites.html#min_requirements" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;high minimum requirements&lt;/a&gt;, so it&amp;rsquo;s not a good fit to use on a Raspberry Pi:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 vCPUs, either x86_64 or arm64 architecture. Also, higher clock frequency is preferred to higher core count.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 GB RAM.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Not supported: &lt;em&gt;Single-board computers such as Raspberry Pi. To run your code on a Raspberry Pi, check out remote interpreters or remote debugging, and similar features.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id="remote-development-with-intellij-idea"&gt;Remote Development with IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use IntelliJ IDEA to develop on a remote machine (Windows, Linux, or macOS) with code on the Raspberry Pi. Make sure you have the Remote Development Gateway plugin enabled as described on &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea/remote-development-starting-page.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Connect to a remote server from IntelliJ IDEA&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.jetbrains.com/help/idea/jetbrains-gateway.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Install JetBrains Gateway﻿&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Using Maven Archetype</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/development/developing-on-a-remote-pc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/development/developing-on-a-remote-pc/</guid><description>&lt;div class="notices tip" &gt;&lt;p&gt;GITHUB PROJECT: &lt;a href="https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-maven-archetype" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-maven-archetype&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="developing-java-programs-using-a-remote-pc-workstation"&gt;Developing Java Programs Using a Remote PC Workstation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing your Java program, compiling and running it directly on the Raspberry Pi board
as shown in the previous chapter is perfectly fine, of course,
but there is an alternative way to arrange your developing laboratory, using a normal
desktop computer as Remote Developing Workstation (RDW).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href="https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-maven-archetype" title="raspimaven-archetype" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Maven Archetype&lt;/a&gt; will give you
a tool to generate Pi4J V2+ skeleton Java projects. You can use it for your next Pi4j project and you will be able
to develop your program on the remote workstation (RDW), compile them, transmit the executable
code on the target Pi board and run it. You can also start a remote debugging session.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>