<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ADS1115 on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/ads1115/</link><description>Recent content in ADS1115 on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/ads1115/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sensor drivers</title><link>https://pi4j.com/featured-projects/sensor-drivers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/featured-projects/sensor-drivers/</guid><description>In case you want to read the data from various I2C sensors connected to Raspberry Pi the difficult part is usually writing a piece of code which talks to the I2C sensor.
rpi-drivers is a Java library implementing simple APIs and communication code for some widely used I2C sensors. You can easily measure temperature, pressure and humidity, get ambient light intensity or measure voltage in your java Raspberry Pi projects.</description></item><item><title>AD Converter ADS1115</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ads1115/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ads1115/</guid><description>Description The Analog Digital Converter Ads1115 is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. The ADS1115 device is a precision, low-power, 16-bit, I2C-compatible, analog-to-digital converter (ADCs). The ADS1115 device incorporates a low-drift voltage reference and an oscillator as well as a programmable gain amplifier (PGA) and a digital comparator. These features, along with a wide operating supply range, makes the ADS1115 well suited for power- and space-constrained, sensor measurement applications.</description></item><item><title>Joystick Analog</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/joystickanalog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/joystickanalog/</guid><description>Description The JoystickAnalog is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. The template class is created for an analog joystick, for example the KY-023, which consists of two potentiometers, one for the X-axis and one for the Y-axis. But any joystick with two potentiometers will meet the requirements.
The basic functions of the template class are:
return of a normalized value, optionally between 0 and 1 or between -1 and 1, of the X-axis and the Y-axis creation of simple events at a value change of the X-axis or the Y-axis, simple event handlers for button pressed, button depressed, while button is pressed calibration of the center position of the joystick (center position 0.</description></item></channel></rss>