<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Potentiometer on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/potentiometer/</link><description>Recent content in Potentiometer on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/potentiometer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Component Examples</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/</guid><description>The FHNW University contributed a full project with example implementations of the following devices.
Current available components Device(s) Developed by Link Simple Button Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Simple LED Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices AD Converter ADS1115 Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Buzzer Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Camera Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Joystick Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Joystick Analog Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices LCD Display Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices LED Button Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices LED Matrix Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices LED Strip Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Potentiometer Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Servo Motor Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Simple Implementation For a Simple Implementation, the recommendation is to use the Launcher Class.</description></item><item><title>Potentiometer</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/potentiometer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/potentiometer/</guid><description>Description The Potentiometer is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. The constructor of the class requires an ADS1115 object. In addition, the channel, with which the AD converter evaluates the current position of the sliding contact must be defined. For normalization, the maximum voltage that can drop across the sliding contact must also be specified. Any commercially available potentiometer with three connections (fixed resistor and the slider) can be evaluated with this class.</description></item></channel></rss>