<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>I2C on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/i2c/</link><description>Recent content in I2C on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/i2c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Inter-Integrated Circuit (I²C)</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/io-examples/i2c/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/io-examples/i2c/</guid><description>What is it? I²C (spoken as I-Squared-C) is a bus originally invented by Philips. It is designed as a classic master-slave bus. A data transfer is always i nitiated by a master. It can also be set up in a multi-master system. I²C is connected via two signal lines (data line and clock line). The transmission rate of the bus can be between 0.1 Mbit/s up to 3.4 Mbit/s depending on the clock rate.</description></item><item><title>I²C Clock Stretching</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/io-examples/i2c/clock-stretching/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/io-examples/i2c/clock-stretching/</guid><description>Clock Stretching Please be aware there are some hardware issues when using the Raspberry Pi with devices that expect to be able to use clock stretching, for more info see &amp;ldquo;Adventures in I2C: clock stretching on the Raspberry Pi&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;I2C stretch bug. Been fixed or not?&amp;quot;.
Clock stretching in I2C allows a slave device to halt the master before a more data is sent. This is often the case when the slave device writes to an EEPROM etc.</description></item><item><title>Ongoing I2C Improvements</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240418_i2c_improvements/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240418_i2c_improvements/</guid><description>2024-04-17, by Frank Delporte
Robert von Burg is working on improvements of the I2C implementation in Pi4J in preparation for the next release. The changes are in pull request #351. It&amp;rsquo;s still work-in-progress but will bring these improvements:
New I2C.execute(Callable) method to allow to atomically execute multiple I2C calls in a thread in a safe way. New I2C.writeRead(byte[], byte[]) method to atomically perform a write, immediately followed by a read on the I2C bus.</description></item></channel></rss>