<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PWM Hardware Support on RPi5</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240423_pwm_rpi5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240423_pwm_rpi5/</guid><description>2024-04-23, by Tom Aarts
The next version of Pi4J (are now already in 2.5.2-SNAPSHOT) will add PWM support via a new provider linuxfs-pwm. The previous PWM PiGpio provider does not support the Raspberry Pi 5 RP1 chip. To use this new provider, changes are required in your pom.xml dependencies and Java code. The details of using this new provider are explained in the Pi4J documentation in Pulse Width Modulation. In this blog post, I want to provide extra details and an example implementation.</description></item><item><title>Interview Robert von Burg</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240419_interview_robert_von_burg/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240419_interview_robert_von_burg/</guid><description>2024-04-19, by Frank Delporte
The Pi4J project has two important Roberts. The first one is Robert Savage (living in the US), who started the Pi4J development. You can read more about him and the reason Pi4J was created in this interview on Foojay. He also created V2 of Pi4J, but hasn&amp;rsquo;t been involved a lot in the project since its release. Luckily, we have another Robert in the Pi4J team! Robert von Burg (living in Switzerland), also known as Eitch, is the main maintainer now of the Pi4J V2 sources and takes care of the releases.</description></item><item><title>Ongoing I2C Improvements</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240418_i2c_improvements/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240418_i2c_improvements/</guid><description>2024-04-17, by Frank Delporte
Robert von Burg is working on improvements of the I2C implementation in Pi4J in preparation for the next release. The changes are in pull request #351. It&amp;rsquo;s still work-in-progress but will bring these improvements:
New I2C.execute(Callable) method to allow to atomically execute multiple I2C calls in a thread in a safe way. New I2C.writeRead(byte[], byte[]) method to atomically perform a write, immediately followed by a read on the I2C bus.</description></item><item><title>LED Matrix with SPI MAX7219</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240417_led_matrix_max7219_spi_web/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240417_led_matrix_max7219_spi_web/</guid><description>2024-04-18, by Frank Delporte
Roberto Marquez shared a project with us that uses Java to interface with a MAX7219 SPI device to control an LED matrix. It&amp;rsquo;s inspired by the blog Raspberry Pi and SPI 8×8 LED matrix example with Java and Pi4j, but differs in that it is Web-enabled via Spring Boot. This project is the starting point to create a weather station in combination with the BMP280, see BME280 Sensor (temp, humidity, pressure) via Pi4J, I2C, and JBang.</description></item><item><title>Alexander Liggesmeyer and RPi5</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240318_interview_alexander_liggesmeyer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240318_interview_alexander_liggesmeyer/</guid><description>2024-03-18, by Frank Delporte
Interview with Alexander Liggesmeyer about Pi4J for Raspberry Pi 5 Today, version 2.5.0 of Pi4J got released with many changes, fixes and improvements. The most important one being support for the Raspberry Pi 5. Short after the release of this new board, several issues were raised on GitHub as Pi4J was not compatible. The Raspberry Pi 5 uses a completely new way to interact with the GPIOs: the RP1 chip.</description></item><item><title>Pi4J Operating System</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2023/20230731_pi4j_os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2023/20230731_pi4j_os/</guid><description>2023-07-31, by Frank Delporte and Dieter Holz
Yes, the Raspberry Pi Operating System is awesome! But the Pi4J project made it if even more awesome by adding &amp;ldquo;goodies&amp;rdquo; for Java developers! Pi4J OS is not yet another OS, but the official Raspberry Pi OS, with additional tools and preconfigurations to make it the ideal OS for any Java and JavaFX developer who wants to use a Raspberry Pi.
The project is shared on GitHub and documented on the Pi4J website.</description></item><item><title>LED strip with Pi4J and JBang</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2022/20221128_led_strip_with_jbang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2022/20221128_led_strip_with_jbang/</guid><description>2022-11-28, by Robert von Burg
Intro In an earlier post, JBang and Pi4J were used to control a LED and button connected to a Raspberry Pi.
This week Robert von Burg, one of the main contributors of the Pi4J project, shared on Mastodon another project where a LED strip is controlled via I2C.
This is the result, notice the Foojay.io startup artwork 😉
Wiring The Raspberry Pi in the video is attached to a custom PCB used by Robert in medical cabinets.</description></item><item><title>Kotlin on the Raspberry Pi</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2022/20221117_kotlin_on_raspberrypi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2022/20221117_kotlin_on_raspberrypi/</guid><description>2022-11-17, by Muhammad Hashim
Intro Pi4J is considered the project that brought the JVM to the RaspberryPi.
It has been up for more than a decade allowing developers to write sophisticated, high-level, yet simple software on the RaspberryPi.
And we’re glad to make it even more simpler and powerful!
For quite some years now Kotlin has been a most welcome language in the JVM ecosystem and the modern development toolchain.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started Template</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2022/20220113_javafx_pi4j_template/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2022/20220113_javafx_pi4j_template/</guid><description>2022-01-13, by Frank Delporte
Intro The Pi4J project wants to be the starting point for everyone who wants to use Java on the Raspberry Pi, being it a headless, JavaFX-user interface and/or GPIO-controller project.
Pi4J is intended to provide a friendly object-oriented I/O API and implementation libraries for Java Programmers to access the full I/O capabilities of the Raspberry Pi platform. This project abstracts the low-level native integration and interrupt monitoring to enable Java programmers to focus on implementing their application business logic.</description></item></channel></rss>