<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Button on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/button/</link><description>Recent content in Button on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/button/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Minimal Example</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/jbang/jbang_minimal_example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/jbang/jbang_minimal_example/</guid><description>Minimal Pi4J with JBang example GITHUB PROJECT: github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-jbang &amp;gt; Pi4JMinimalExample.java
Intro Before proceeding with this example, make sure that you have a Raspberry Pi prepared to execute Java code with JBang as explained here.
The following example is based on the &amp;ldquo;Minimal example application&amp;rdquo;, and uses the same wiring with a button and LED. By using JBang we can run this project with a single file without the need of a full Maven or Gradle project, or compiling the Java code.</description></item><item><title>Simple Button</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/simplebutton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/simplebutton/</guid><description>Description The SimpleButton is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project.
The Template Class gives you the option to check the state of the button, and to create simple events if the button is pressed, depressed or while it is being pressed.
Layout Simple Button Breadboard
Big Button
Code A simple example on how to use the Button-Class from the Hardware-Catalog:</description></item><item><title>LED Button</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledbutton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledbutton/</guid><description>Description The LedButton is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. You can take any Button with a LED you want to. Like for example the big button bellow in the picture gallery.
The Template Class gives you the option to check the state of the button, and to create simple events if the button is pressed or depressed, or the whole time is is being pressed.</description></item></channel></rss>