<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Project source structure on Pi4J</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/</link><description>Recent content in Project source structure on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Build Instructions</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/build-instructions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/build-instructions/</guid><description>Building the Pi4J Project is simple and requires minimal effort. Pi4J is primarily built using Apache Maven and Java 11. Pi4J can be built directly on your host computer or inside a Docker container where all toolchains and dependencies are already installed, configuired and cached.
If you wish to build using a Docker container, please skip ahead to the Building with Docker topic.
Prerequsites In order to build Pi4J, the host system must have the following toolchains pre-installed.</description></item><item><title>Maven settings</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/maven-settings/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/maven-settings/</guid><description>To simplify development but not commit sensitive information, you can add personal or PC-specific settings in the Maven settings.xml file. This file is stored or needs to be created in the &amp;ldquo;.m2&amp;rdquo; directory in your home directory:
Windows: C:\Users\YOUR_NAME.m2 Linux: /home/YOUR_NAME/.m2 Mac: /Users/YOUR_NAME/.m2 For more info see this article on Baeldung.
This is an example settings file, including settings for compiling of Pi4J and credentials to upload the generated code to a Raspberry Pi.</description></item><item><title>Code styling</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/code-styling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/code-styling/</guid><description>To prevent unnecessary code (tabs versus spaces, number of characters per line&amp;hellip;) we have defined an editorconfig for IntelliJ IDEA. You can find more info here about its use.
Some tips to keep the code clean and readable:
Short methods with a clear name Use SonarLint to get improvement tips while code Use shortcuts CTRL+ALT+L: Reformat code CTRL+ALT+O: Optimize imports</description></item><item><title>Hardware testing</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/hardware-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/architecture/about-the-code/hardware-testing/</guid><description>This is an experimental project which will need a lot of love&amp;hellip; The new Raspberry Pi Pico with a lot of GPIOs for a very low price, seems even to be a better fit for this project compared to the Arduino Due&amp;hellip; To be further investigated!
To minimize the required time and efforts to test a new release, V2 aims to include an automated test which performs I/O testing on each I/O interface on each model of RPi.</description></item></channel></rss>