<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Advanced on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/architecture/advanced/</link><description>Recent content in Advanced on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/architecture/advanced/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Native Library Path</title><link>https://pi4j.com/architecture/advanced/library-path/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/architecture/advanced/library-path/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="overview"&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some Pi4J plugins, such as the Pi4J PiGpio Provider plugin, depend on native JNI libraries to communicate with the
underlying system. By default Pi4J embeds these native libraries as resources inside the plugin&amp;rsquo;s JAR file. At
runtime Pi4J extracts the native library into a temporary directory so the JVM can load the library from the filesystem.
Upon termination the temporary file is automatically removed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This automatic extration behavior works well for most users; however, there are certain edge cases where this may fail.
On failure, its common to see a &lt;code&gt;UnsatisfiedLinkError&lt;/code&gt; on startup of your application or when you create a Pi4J context.
Edge cases such as the following may require customization of the runtime to deal with native library loading.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Plug-ins</title><link>https://pi4j.com/architecture/advanced/plugins/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/architecture/advanced/plugins/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The goal of Pi4J V2+ is to provide a solid base with all required &amp;ldquo;minimal functionality&amp;rdquo; while at the same time, promote third-party development and extensibility, thus enabling developers to build and maintain their extensions outside of the Pi4J core projects codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will enable us to deliver a stable, fully tested framework as the number of features inside of Pi4J can be limited and support for specific I/O hardware can be provided with an extension for Pi4J.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>