<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Maven on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/maven/</link><description>Recent content in Maven on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/maven/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Developing on a remote PC</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/developing-on-a-remote-pc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/developing-on-a-remote-pc/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-maven-archetype
Developing Java programs using a remote PC workstation Writing your Java program, compiling and running it directly on the Raspberry Pi board as shown in the previous chapter is perfectly fine, of course, but there is an alternative way to arrange your developing laboratory, using a normal desktop computer as Remote Developing Workstation (RDW).
This Maven Archetype will give you a tool to generate Pi4J-V2 skeleton Java projects.</description></item><item><title>Minimal example application</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/minimal-example-application/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/minimal-example-application/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-example-minimal
In the &amp;ldquo;pi4j-example-minimal&amp;rdquo; GitHub project you can find a project which contains the minimal code to control a digital input and output with Pi4J. The project is further described on this page. The application will toggle an LED on/off and each time you press the button, the toggling speed increases. When you have pushed the button 5 times, the application stops.
Wiring This minimal example application uses this wiring:</description></item><item><title>User interface with JavaFX</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/user-interface-with-javafx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/user-interface-with-javafx/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-example-javafx
JavaFX is a framework to create user interfaces for desktop (Windows, Mac, Linux) and mobile phones. JavaFX is an opensource project which is documented on openjfx.io and the sources are available in this GitHub project.
The main goal of Java has always been to be able to create applications which are &amp;ldquo;write once, run everywhere&amp;rdquo;. JavaFX promises the same for Graphical User Interface applications.
Gluon is the main maintainer of the OpenJFX project and offers commercial support to companies who want to use JavaFX in critical applications.</description></item><item><title>JavaFX GUI and MVC template</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/javafx-mvc-template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/javafx-mvc-template/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-template-javafx
The FHNW University created a template project which is now part of the Pi4J example repositories.
The goal of this project is to:
Provide a clear step-by-step how to prepare your Raspberry Pi Provide multiple test and start applications Explain the use of a MVC-model (Model-View-Controller) to clearly split data, actions and user interface Explain the use of JUnit test Sources and info Please check the README of the sources of the project for a full description of the setup process of the Raspberry Pi and to fully understand the example applications and the MVC-model.</description></item></channel></rss>