<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>LED on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/led/</link><description>Recent content in LED on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/led/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Component Examples</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/</guid><description>The FHNW University contributed a full project with example implementations of the following devices.
Current available components Device(s) Developed by Link Simple Button Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Simple LED Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices AD Converter ADS1115 Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Buzzer Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Camera Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Joystick Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Joystick Analog Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices LCD Display Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices LED Button Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices LED Matrix Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices LED Strip Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Potentiometer Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Servo Motor Reto Stutz, Mike Schoder Example Devices Simple Implementation For a Simple Implementation, the recommendation is to use the Launcher Class.</description></item><item><title>Binary Clock</title><link>https://pi4j.com/featured-projects/binary-clock/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/featured-projects/binary-clock/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: github.com/taartspi/pi4j-binary-clock
This project by Tom Aarts (published on May 15, 2024), is a binary clock created with LEDs on a breadboard. In the video below you see it incrementing to the next minute and hour. What you see is the Hour Minute and Second displayed in BCD (Binary Coded Decimal):
Design document describing the LED PCF8575 connections, and the Java implementation that drives the clock LEDs. Note: there are two PCF8575 IC used in this design.</description></item><item><title>Minimal Example</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/jbang/jbang_minimal_example/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/jbang/jbang_minimal_example/</guid><description>Minimal Pi4J with JBang example GITHUB PROJECT: github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-jbang &amp;gt; Pi4JMinimalExample.java
Intro Before proceeding with this example, make sure that you have a Raspberry Pi prepared to execute Java code with JBang as explained here.
The following example is based on the &amp;ldquo;Minimal example application&amp;rdquo;, and uses the same wiring with a button and LED. By using JBang we can run this project with a single file without the need of a full Maven or Gradle project, or compiling the Java code.</description></item><item><title>8x8 LED Matrix</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/jbang/jbang_pi4j_spi_led_matrix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/jbang/jbang_pi4j_spi_led_matrix/</guid><description>Controlling a 8x8 LED Matrix with MAX7219 via SPI GITHUB PROJECT: github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-jbang &amp;gt; Pi4JLedMatrixSpi.java
This example is explained in the following video:
Intro Before proceeding with this example, make sure that you have a Raspberry Pi prepared to execute Java code with JBang as explained here.
Wiring SPI requires four connections, but as we don&amp;rsquo;t read data back, we only connect three of them plus power and ground.
BCM 10 (MOSI) to DIN BCM 11 (SCLK) to CLK BCM 8 (CE0) to CS 5V to VCC Ground to ground Wiring between Raspberry Pi and matrix</description></item><item><title>Simple LED</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/simpleled/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/simpleled/</guid><description>Description The SimpleLed is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project.
The template Class gives you the option to switch off, switch on or toggle the state of the LED.
Layout Simple Led Breadboard
Code A simple example on how to use the LED-Class from the Hardware-Catalog:
System.out.println(&amp;#34;Simple LED demo started ...&amp;#34;); // Create a new SimpleLED component SimpleLed led = new SimpleLed(pi4j, PIN.D26); // Turn on the LED to have a defined state System.</description></item><item><title>LED Button</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledbutton/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/components/ledbutton/</guid><description>Description The LedButton is a template class, that you can use in your own Java-project. You can take any Button with a LED you want to. Like for example the big button bellow in the picture gallery.
The Template Class gives you the option to check the state of the button, and to create simple events if the button is pressed or depressed, or the whole time is is being pressed.</description></item></channel></rss>