<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>BME280 on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/bme280/</link><description>Recent content in BME280 on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/bme280/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sensor drivers</title><link>https://pi4j.com/featured-projects/sensor-drivers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/featured-projects/sensor-drivers/</guid><description>In case you want to read the data from various I2C sensors connected to Raspberry Pi the difficult part is usually writing a piece of code which talks to the I2C sensor.
rpi-drivers is a Java library implementing simple APIs and communication code for some widely used I2C sensors. You can easily measure temperature, pressure and humidity, get ambient light intensity or measure voltage in your java Raspberry Pi projects.</description></item><item><title>BME280 Sensor</title><link>https://pi4j.com/examples/jbang/bme280_temperature_humidity_pressure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/examples/jbang/bme280_temperature_humidity_pressure/</guid><description>BME280 Sensor (temp, humidity, pressure) via Pi4J, I2C, and JBang GITHUB PROJECT: github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-jbang &amp;gt; Pi4JTempHumPressI2C.java and github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-jbang &amp;gt; Pi4JTempHumPressSpi.java
Intro This is an example project to demonstrate how to read the temperature, humidity and pressure from a BME280 sensor, installed on an Adafruit board that can be controlled via I2C and SPI. Such a sensor itself is a very tiny component that can be integrated in phones and many other types of devices.</description></item><item><title>Bosch sensor gas measurement</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240517_bme680_gas_measurement/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240517_bme680_gas_measurement/</guid><description>2024-05-17, by Frank Delporte
Bosch has several sensors which are extremely small to measure temperature, humidity, pressure, and gas. We also have several example implementations documented on the Pi4J website:
BME280 Sensor (temp, humidity, pressure) via Pi4J, I2C, and JBang. BMP280 Sensor, example implementation by Thomas Aarts. LED Matrix with SPI MAX7219, work-in-progress for a weather station. Sensor drivers, project by Juraj Veverka. You can find easy-to-use boards with such a sensor, for instance, on:</description></item><item><title>LED Matrix with SPI MAX7219</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240417_led_matrix_max7219_spi_web/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240417_led_matrix_max7219_spi_web/</guid><description>2024-04-18, by Frank Delporte
Roberto Marquez shared a project with us that uses Java to interface with a MAX7219 SPI device to control an LED matrix. It&amp;rsquo;s inspired by the blog Raspberry Pi and SPI 8×8 LED matrix example with Java and Pi4j, but differs in that it is Web-enabled via Spring Boot. This project is the starting point to create a weather station in combination with the BMP280, see BME280 Sensor (temp, humidity, pressure) via Pi4J, I2C, and JBang.</description></item></channel></rss>