<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Previous versions (V.1)</title><link>https://pi4j.com/about/previous-version-v1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/about/previous-version-v1/</guid><description>Documentation of the 1.X versions Pi4J Version 1.4 Released 2021-03-03 Support for JDK/JRE 11 and 64-bit ARM platforms This release is the final release for the Pi4J Version 1.x codebase The Pi4J project is now prioritizing focus on providing Java programs access, control and communication with the core I/O capabilities of the Raspberry Pi platform Changed project to Apache License, Version 2.0 Removed pi4j-device and pi4j-gpio-extension library Removed platform support for Odroid, BananaPi, BPi, NanoPi, OrangePi Various improvements and bug fixes listed here: GitHub Issues (v1.</description></item><item><title>What's New (V.2)</title><link>https://pi4j.com/about/new-in-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/about/new-in-v2/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s New in 2.0? Pi4J version 2.0 brings with it many new features, and an entirely new architecture that focuses on extensibility, simplified integration and a modern Java API including the following:
Fluent APIs/Interfaces Immutable Runtime Context Extensible Provider/Platform/Plug-in Architecture Builder-patterns for creating new I/O instances Well-documented source code Hardware PWM Support Java 11 Future plans:
Dependency Injection via Pi4J Annotations Remote I/O Support (via TCP/IP) In addition to the features listed above, Pi4J version 2.</description></item><item><title>Release Notes</title><link>https://pi4j.com/about/release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/about/release-notes/</guid><description>All releases of Pi4J V.2 are listed on github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-v2/releases.
2024-03-18 - V2.5.0 With over 100 commits from multiple branches, this is a major release with many improvements! With many thanks to the core team (Robert von Burg, Tom Aarts), and a major addition of Alexander Liggesmeyer, Pi4J is again lifted to a higher level!
You can find out more about Alexander in this blog post.
Changes in 2.5.0 A new GpioD Provider adds support for the Raspberry Pi 5.</description></item><item><title>Pi4J Downloads</title><link>https://pi4j.com/about/download/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/about/download/</guid><description>All downloads provided by the project can be found on pi4j.com/download.
The compiled artifacts (releases and snapshots) are available in the Sonatype Maven repository.</description></item><item><title>License (Open Source)</title><link>https://pi4j.com/about/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/about/license/</guid><description>The Pi4J Version 2.0 project is distributed and licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 license (A business-friendly OSS license).
apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0 github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-v2/blob/master/LICENSE.txt Apache License Version 2.0, January 2004 http://www.apache.org/licenses/ TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR USE, REPRODUCTION, AND DISTRIBUTION
Definitions.
&amp;ldquo;License&amp;rdquo; shall mean the terms and conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution as defined by Sections 1 through 9 of this document.
&amp;ldquo;Licensor&amp;rdquo; shall mean the copyright owner or entity authorized by the copyright owner that is granting the License.</description></item><item><title>The Team</title><link>https://pi4j.com/about/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/about/team/</guid><description>Robert Savage, Project Founder, Architect, Lead Developer.
Principal Software Architect/Engineer. Consultant, technology enthusiast, entrepreneur, open source contributor, technology blogger. Founder at shadeBlue, LLC and SavageSoftware, LLC. Robert has a more than 20 year career working in the professional audio visual and home/commercial automation industry and an extensive background in developing technology solutions with a special focus on home automation and hardware/firmware/software integration.</description></item></channel></rss>