<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Pi4J</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/</link><description>Recent content in About on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://v2.pi4j.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Previous versions (V1)</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/previous-version-v1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/previous-version-v1/</guid><description>Documentation of the 1.X versions Pi4J Version 1.4 ONGOING Experimental build using JDK11 Not using Java-modules, this will be part of the V2 Documentation website V1.4 Pi4J Version 1.3 Released 2021-01-29 Added support for Raspberry Pi 4B, 400, and Compute Module 4 Various improvements and bug fixes listed here: GitHub Issues (v1.3) Based on JDK8 Documentation website V1.3 Pi4J Version 1.2 Released 2019-02-26 Based on Java 8 Documentation website V1.</description></item><item><title>What's New (V2)</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/new-in-v2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/new-in-v2/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s New in 2.0? Pi4J version 2.0 brings with it many new features, and an entirely new architecture that focuses on extensibility, simplified integration and a modern Java API including the following:
Fluent APIs/Interfaces Immutable Runtime Context Extensible Provider/Platform/Plug-in Architecture Builder-patterns for creating new I/O instances Dependency Injection via Pi4J Annotations Well-documented source code Hardware PWM Support Remote I/O Support (via TCP/IP) Java 11 In addition to the features listed above, Pi4J version 2.</description></item><item><title>Release Notes</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/release-notes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/release-notes/</guid><description>Release note are not available as this project does not yet have any releases.</description></item><item><title>License (Open Source)</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/license/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/license/</guid><description>The Pi4J Version 2.0 project is distributed and licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 license (A business-friendly OSS license).
apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0 github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-v2/blob/master/LICENSE.txt Apache License Version 2.0, January 2004 http://www.apache.org/licenses/ TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR USE, REPRODUCTION, AND DISTRIBUTION
Definitions.
&amp;ldquo;License&amp;rdquo; shall mean the terms and conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution as defined by Sections 1 through 9 of this document.
&amp;ldquo;Licensor&amp;rdquo; shall mean the copyright owner or entity authorized by the copyright owner that is granting the License.</description></item><item><title>The Team</title><link>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://v2.pi4j.com/about/team/</guid><description>Robert Savage, Project Founder, Architect, Lead Developer. Principal Software Architect/Engineer. Consultant, technology enthusiast, entrepreneur, open source contributor, technology blogger. Founder at shadeBlue, LLC and SavageSoftware, LLC. Robert has a more than 20 year career working in the professional audio visual and home/commercial automation industry and an extensive background in developing technology solutions with a special focus on home automation and hardware/firmware/software integration.</description></item></channel></rss>