<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>PWM on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/pwm/</link><description>Recent content in PWM on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/pwm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>LinuxFS Provider</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/providers/linuxfs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/providers/linuxfs/</guid><description>The current implementation of the LinuxFS plugin implements a file based I2C and PWM provider. The file based I2C provider opens /dev/i2c-1 using a RandomAccessFile to perform I2C reads and writes. The file based PWM provider opens /sys/class/pwm/pwmchip? using a RandomAccessFile to perform PWM operations.
The Linuxfs provider linuxfs-pwm requires minimum kernel Bullseye 6.1.21 and Bookworm 6.6.22 !
Providers in the LinuxFS plugin:
linuxfs-i2c linuxfs-pwm Under construction linuxfs-digital-input linuxfs-digital-output To use the LinuxFS provider include the following dependencies:</description></item><item><title>PiGpio Provider</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/providers/pigpio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/providers/pigpio/</guid><description>The current implementation of the PiGpio exposes the GPIO functions available on the Raspberry Pi.
Providers in the PiGpio plugin:
pigpio-digital-input pigpio-digital-output pigpio-pwm pigpio-i2c pigpio-spi pigpio-serial Applications which use the PiGpio Provider, need to be started with sudo to be able to interface with the GPIOs.
When you don&amp;rsquo;t use sudo, you&amp;rsquo;ll see an error like this:
WARN com.pi4j.library.pigpio.impl.PiGpioNativeImpl - PIGPIO ERROR: PI_INIT_FAILED; pigpio initialisation failed To use the PiGpio provider include the following dependencies:</description></item><item><title>Pulse Width Modulation (PWM)</title><link>https://pi4j.com/documentation/io-examples/pwm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/documentation/io-examples/pwm/</guid><description>What is it? The abbreviation PWM stands for &amp;ldquo;Pulse Width Modulation&amp;rdquo; and is also often referred to in German as pulse width modulation or pulse duration modulation. This technology is used, among other things, to control servomotors and is also used, for example, for the fans of a regular computer.
With PWM, it is possible to control a component such as a motor no longer purely binary, i.e. off (0% power) or on (100% power), but to control them almost at will.</description></item><item><title>PWM Hardware Support on RPi5</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240423_pwm_rpi5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2024/20240423_pwm_rpi5/</guid><description>2024-04-23, by Tom Aarts
The next version of Pi4J (are now already in 2.5.2-SNAPSHOT) will add PWM support via a new provider linuxfs-pwm. The previous PWM PiGpio provider does not support the Raspberry Pi 5 RP1 chip. To use this new provider, changes are required in your pom.xml dependencies and Java code. The details of using this new provider are explained in the Pi4J documentation in Pulse Width Modulation. In this blog post, I want to provide extra details and an example implementation.</description></item></channel></rss>