<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>JavaFX on Pi4J</title><link>https://pi4j.com/tags/javafx/</link><description>Recent content in JavaFX on Pi4J</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pi4j.com/tags/javafx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>User interface with JavaFX</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/user-interface-with-javafx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/user-interface-with-javafx/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-example-javafx
JavaFX is a framework to create user interfaces for desktop (Windows, Mac, Linux) and mobile phones. JavaFX is an opensource project which is documented on openjfx.io and the sources are available in this GitHub project.
The main goal of Java has always been to be able to create applications which are &amp;ldquo;write once, run everywhere&amp;rdquo;. JavaFX promises the same for Graphical User Interface applications.
Gluon is the main maintainer of the OpenJFX project and offers commercial support to companies who want to use JavaFX in critical applications.</description></item><item><title>Game development with FXGL</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/fxgl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/fxgl/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-example-fxgl
As described on the previous page you can use JavaFX to build user interfaces which behave exactly the same on your PC and Raspberry Pi. Let&amp;rsquo;s go a step further and make a game with an &amp;ldquo;Arcade&amp;rdquo; controller.
For this project, we will be using FXGL, an opensource library on top of JavaFX to build games.
The image of the crowpi project has every prerequisite installed to work with javaFX/FXGL</description></item><item><title>JavaFX GUI and MVC template</title><link>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/javafx-mvc-template/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/getting-started/javafx-mvc-template/</guid><description>GITHUB PROJECT: https://github.com/Pi4J/pi4j-template-javafx
The FHNW University created a template project which is now part of the Pi4J example repositories.
The goal of this project is to:
Provide a clear step-by-step how to prepare your Raspberry Pi Provide multiple test and start applications Explain the use of a MVC-model (Model-View-Controller) to clearly split data, actions and user interface Explain the use of JUnit test Sources and info Please check the README of the sources of the project for a full description of the setup process of the Raspberry Pi and to fully understand the example applications and the MVC-model.</description></item><item><title>Pi4J Operating System</title><link>https://pi4j.com/blog/2023/20230731_pi4j_os/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://pi4j.com/blog/2023/20230731_pi4j_os/</guid><description>Yes, the Raspberry Pi Operating System is awesome! But the Pi4J project made it if even more awesome by adding &amp;ldquo;goodies&amp;rdquo; for Java developers! Pi4J OS is not yet another OS, but the official Raspberry Pi OS, with additional tools and preconfigurations to make it the ideal OS for any Java and JavaFX developer who wants to use a Raspberry Pi.
The project is shared on GitHub and documented on the Pi4J website.</description></item></channel></rss>